# **BRIAN SHIPOS**

2405 NE 113th Street #5, Seattle, Washington 98125 | 804.938.9903 | bshipos@gmail.com

# **OBJECTIVE**

Utilize my ability to adapt to fast changing priorities and quickly master new tasks to switch careers into the programming field as a Level 1 Engineer. I have a Bachelor of Science degree in Graphic Design and 14+ years working in an environment with competing deadlines and a focus on teamwork to achieve goals.

#### **SKILLS**

Beginner Javascript (ES6, ES7)	Beginner HTML5	Microsoft Office
Beginner Python 3	Beginner CSS3	Adobe Creative Suite
Beginner VCS (Git)	React ISX exposure	Dreamweaver

## **EXPERIENCE**

## RECENT LEARNING

• The-Other-Ansible: a chatroom project exploring front end and back end JS and React JSX. Project included creating the HTML and CSS page as a template and then adding functionality to the page through JS. Included set up of a REST server API using nodeJS and Express. Once basic functionality had been established I began the exercise of converting the site to ReactJSX.

#### STORE MANAGER | FEDEX OFFICE AND PRINT CENTER | 9/2008 - PRESENT

- · Promoted to Senior Store Manager 6/2018
- Fostering communication, teamwork, and unity among the team that allows for sharing of ideas and positions yet celebrates diversity and different viewpoints.
- · Monitoring metrics, forecasting, and business practices to adhere to company expectations and goals.
- · Performing sales calls with new and existing clients to foster revenue growth and repeat business.
- · Maintaining schedules, payroll, and approval of time worked.
- · Working with Human Resources to recruit, interview, select, and hire new employees.
- Leading team members using a performance counseling process to identify positive and negative behaviors and provide structured steps to improve areas of opportunity.
- · Working closely with customers and businesses in order to foster a positive image of the company and provide excellent service.

## FEDEX KINKO'S | 02/2004-09/2008

- · Production Operator -> Senior Project Coordinator -> Assistant Manager
- · Operation of machines and running production to ensure jobs are completed on time and correctly.
- · Provide leadership for the shift, prioritize, and manage projects from order entry to delivery.
- · Providing leadership and management assistance in support of the Center Manager.

## **EDUCATION**

## BACHELOR OF SCIENCE | 2000-2003 | ART INSTITUTE OF PITTSBURGH

- · Major: Graphic Design.
- Awarded the Dean's Award at graduation with a 3.7 grade point average.
  Courses focused on a variety of technical art experience, including web design and Html, as well as a selection of fine art skills.